翻译：阿蘅阿蘅  跌跌不爱吃青椒  猫中之王  醉芝士
校对：捣蛋鬼赛太公  倒霉蛋YY猫  总监   YY猫
后期：孤帆     时间轴：加森
老爸老妈浪漫史
第九季  第十二集
星期五  晚上8点
离婚礼还有22小时
"让派对开始吧"
"Let's get this party started."
能按下那个按钮吗
Hey, can you push the button?
不许碰那个按钮
Do not touch that button.
-按一下嘛  -别按
- Just give it a little push. - Don't push it.
-按一下  -别听他的
- Just push it a little. - Don't listen to him.
-按一点  按一点  -不许按
- Half of it, halfway, halfway... - Don't even touch it.
我为什么不能按这个按钮
Why can't I push the button?
因为只要巴尼看到按钮  无论什么按钮
Because whenever Barney sees a button-- any button--
他都得按一下
as to push it.
抱歉
Sorry.
你这么生气干嘛啊
Why are you so mad?
因为我的彩排晚宴
Because my rehearsal dinner
本应该在十分钟前开始
was supposed to start ten minutes ago.
但现在我不但没有狼吞虎咽地吃
But instead of stuffing my face with hors d'oeuvres
惦记了好几个月的饭前点心
that I have been dreaming about for months,
反而是在激光枪战游戏场的保安室
I am in a laser tag security office,
等着我的未婚夫因为制造骚乱
waiting for the police to arrest my fiance
而被警察逮捕
for causing a disturbance.
你说了"未婚夫"
Hey, you said "Fiance."
那是个好兆头
That's a good sign.
你觉得按一下那个按钮如何
Now what do you say we give that old button a push?
好好看着我的脸  巴尼
Take a good look at this face, Barney, okay?
这对将来很有帮助
'Cause it'll be useful for the future.
这是我"超级生气"的脸
This is my "Pretty mad" face.
我觉得不是
Well, then, we've got a problem.
因为这更像是你"超级饿"的脸
'Cause it looks a lot like your "pretty hungry" face.
我要错过培根卷无花果了
I'm missing the bacon-wrapped figs!
快点按那个按钮
Please push the button!
这儿怎么这么冷
Why is it so cold in here?
你是想耍阴招逼供吗
You trying to get me to talk or something?
不想
Not really.
其实你只要安静地坐着就可以了
In fact, if you could just sit there quietly...
好吧  我招
Fine, I'll talk.
得从几个月前说起
It all started a few months ago,
我有了一个史上最棒的点子
when I had the most awesome idea ever.
几个月前
激光枪战的彩排晚宴
Laser tag rehearsal dinner!
这是你史上最烂的点子
That might be the worst idea you've ever had,
等于是烂到极致了
which is saying a lot.
说一个我的烂点子
Name one bad idea I've ever had.
无麸质可食用短裤
Gluten-free edible panties.
热狗棒汉堡
Hot dog on a stick on a bun.
充气性爱玩偶救生筏
Inflatable sex toy life raft.
隆胸频道
The breast augmentation channel.
苏格兰纯麦威士忌胶带
Single malt Scotch tape.
竞争市长
The time you ran for mayor.
我还有一万两千个小徽章  上面写着
I still have 12,000 buttons that say,
"我唯一在意的投票[头]在我的裤子里"
"The only poll I care about is in my pants."
巴尼  筹备婚礼的关键是妥协
Barney, planning a wedding is all about compromise.
你还记得
Do you remember that one night,
我们订婚后的那一晚吗
right after we got engaged?
几个月前
婚礼在哪里举行呀
Where is this wedding gonna be, anyway?
我觉得在加拿大结婚挺好的
You know, I thought it might be nice to get married in Canada.
毕竟那是我的家乡...
I mean, it's where I'm from, and...
好吧
Okay.
说吧  早死早超生
Let's have it. Get it over with,
把你们的吐槽通通说出来
get it all out of your system.
我是新郎 我是新郎  由我开始吧
I'm the groom, i'm the groom, I might as well start.
加拿大  我们要伴着碰撞试验傻蛋乐队的歌声
Canada? What, are we gonna walk down the aisle
步入婚姻的殿堂吗
to Crash Test Dummies?
加拿大乐队
该马修了
Play's to Marshall.
加拿大  你们去做什么
Canada? What are you gonna do,
雇一只狗拉的雪橇或搭帐篷吗
hire a regular dog sled or a stretch?
加拿大
Canada?
你们要在蒂姆・霍顿斯店登记吗
Are you registered at Tim Hortons?
加拿大餐饮连锁店
加拿大
Canada.
弹风琴的会带着连指手套吗
Oh, does the organist play wearing mittens?
加拿大  如果新娘带着连指手套
Canada? How are you gonna slip the ring
你要怎么给她戴上戒指啊
the bride's finger if she's wearing mittens?
连续两个连指手套笑话
Two mitten jokes in a row?
那...你们差不多说完了吧
So... you're pretty much done, then?
孩子们  其实还早着呢
Kids... we weren't even close.
加拿大
Canada.
我们要怎么写婚礼请柬
What do we ask on the wedding invitation?
"你要带麋鹿还是驼鹿来啊"
"Will you be having the elk or the moose?"
加拿大
Canada.
你们要穿着雪地靴
What, are you gonna walk down the aisle
走红毯吗
wearing snowshoes?!
加拿大
Canada.
每个人都能买医保吗
What, is everyone gonna have access to universal healthcare
这样大家就不用纠结
so no one has to choose between going bankrupt
到底是选择破产还是治病
and treating a life-threatening illness?
加拿大没有医保者  住院费十分昂贵
加拿大
Canada?
乐队要演奏什么歌给你们第一支舞伴奏呢
W-What's the band gonna play for your first dance?
碰撞试验傻蛋乐队的歌吗
Crash Test Dummies?
有意思的地方在于  傻蛋都能组乐队
See, it's funny 'cause who gets a band?
够了  这只是个想法
Enough. It was just an idea.
好了好了
Okay, okay.
说真的  罗宾  在纽约办婚礼
Seriously, Robin, doing it here in New York
会更方便  因为我们的朋友
would be easier, since all of our friends
和家人大多都在这里
and a lot of our family are here.
但是我不想让你的婚礼留下遗憾
But... I want you to have the wedding that you want.
如果想在加拿大办
So if it's Canada...
你说一声就行
just say the word.
然后用法语再说一遍
And then say it again in French.
加拿大有法语区
看到没  我妥协了
See? I compromised.
好吧
Fine.
那我们举办一个美好高雅的彩排晚宴
We'll just have a nice, tasteful rehearsal dinner.
地点可以定在法国餐厅
Maybe at a French restaurant.
我整好知道个地方
I know just the place.
餐厅名是什么
What's the name of the restaurant?
激  光枪战
La... ser tag.
我刚在想
You know, I was thinking about
要送你们什么婚礼礼物
what to get you guys for a wedding gift.
你们都知道
As you know,
我是送结婚礼物的大师
I'm kind of the wedding gift master.
这次关于彩排晚宴的谈话
And, well, all this talk of the rehearsal dinner
给我一个绝佳的灵感
gives me a fantastic idea.
我想重新去学钢琴
I've been meaning to start taking piano lessons again.
不
No.
-不准弹钢琴  -各位
- No piano time. - Guys!
让我表演个节目啊
Just let me perform something.
我会轻弹钢琴键
I'll-I'll tickle the keys.
肯定很好听
It'll be great.
不行  除非你打扮成列勃拉斯
Not even if you dressed up as Liberace.
美国钢琴演奏家  同性恋
衣着十分华丽
我就打扮成列勃拉斯
What if I dressed up as Liberace?
-同意   -同意
- Sold! - Sold.
本来就这么决定了
And that was the end of it.
谁知道在我的告别单身派对上
Until my bachelor party.
我来猜猜
Let me guess:
有个脱衣舞娘
there was a stripper.
你们玩得挺开心
You had a little fun.
或许还拍了些不雅照
Maybe took some ill-advised pictures.
接着你就发现
Next thing you know,
她快把你勒索到破产了
she's blackmailing you into bankruptcy,
千辛万苦得来的医学学位证只能挂在
and your medical degree's hanging on the wall
激光枪战保安室的墙上
of a laser tag security office!
不是这样的
No.
在告别单身派对的那晚
The night of my bachelor party,
我的朋友们带我去了一家破烂的旅馆
my friends took me to a crappy hotel,
请我的前任未婚妻来跳脱衣舞
hired my ex-fiance to be the stripper,
我一口气输掉几千大洋
I lost thousands of dollars,
好友还被人砍断了手
and my best friend even had his hand cut off.
那可谓是我人生中最倒霉的一晚
It would've been the worst night of all time
但其实那一切是我集智慧
if the whole thing hadn't been a prank
和美貌于一身的未婚妻策划的恶作剧
planned by my beautiful, amazing fiance.
她故意让我难过  就是为了给我
She put me through hell just to give me the best
生命中最大的惊喜  特别是还安排
surprise of my life...which, p.s.,included an appearance
我最爱的演员出现
by my favorite actor--
非A片演员哦
non-porn category.
听起来很不错嘛
Wow, that sounds pretty cool.
是不错  除了一点以外
Yeah. Except pretty not cool,
他总是念叨说也要整我一次
because he kept talking about how he was gonna get me back,
于是  几天之后
and sure enough, a few days later...
罗宾  有件事我实在无法开口
Robin, there's no good way to say this.
我犯下了弥天大错
I've made a huge mistake.
我不能和你举行婚礼了
I can't go through with the wedding.
什么
What?
我真的很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
但我必须在一切无法挽回之前
I-I just... I had to tell you
告诉你真相
before it was too late.
-天啊  你是说真的  -是的
- Oh, my God, you're serious. - Yeah.
既然这是我的公寓
And since this is my apartment,
所以你还是搬出去吧
I think that you should move out.
好吧
Fine.
小狗狗
Puppies!
多精彩的恶作剧  对吧
I know. Great prank, right?
这也太糟糕了
That is awful.
你这人脑子有病吧
You're a frickin' weirdo.
有病到极点的怪胎
Such a weirdo.
小心点  别弄到我袍子
Careful, watch the robe.
总之  基于某些你们和罗宾才懂
Anyway, for reasons only you guys and Robin
而我这种正常人完全不能理解的原因
but nobody normal like me would understand,
她气得发疯
she got cranky.
然后她就定下了规矩
And she laid down the law.
不准再搞惊喜了
No more surprises.
可你不是最爱惊喜吗
But you love surprises.
就像我最爱舔自己一样
Almost as much as I love lickin' myself!
是指我爱舔  不是这只小狗哦
That was me talking, not the puppy.
巴尼  你的惊喜太过分了
Barney, the surprises are out of hand
也该停手了
and they have to stop.
-一言为定  -可是
- Deal? - But...
-一言为定  -人家
-一言为定  -小屁股[音似]
- Deal? - Butt...
巴尼
Barney...
好吧
Fine.
poppycock小狗鸡鸡  还有胡说的意思
说好了
Deal.
真是的
Man.
这"不准搞惊喜"的规定真是太不公平了
This whole "no more surprises" thing is so unfair.
谁会订这种规矩呀
Who does that?
巴尼  "不再有惊喜"
Barney, the "no more surprises" thing
才是婚姻中最棒的地方
is the best part of being married.
真的  每天早上当我醒来
It's true. When I wake up in the morning,
我就知道莉莉的口气是什么味道
I know what Lily's breath is gonna smell like.
就像是玫瑰花的芳香
It's like... roses.
难道你真的愿意结婚以后
Do you really want a marriage
每天疑神疑鬼猜测
where you have this paranoia
罗宾是不是躲在每个角落
that Robin's hiding around every corner,
策划各种恶作剧来报复你
planning to get you back with some crazy new prank?
你说得太对了
You're absolutely right.
谢谢你  莉莉
Thank you, Lily.
不对  是我说的  我在这里
No, th... that was me, over here.
他根本就没听进去
He wasn't listening.
如果你们说的
If you guys are saying
和我想的是同一个意思的话
what I think you're saying...
应该不一样  你继续
Probably not. Go on.
那就一定表示
...then that must mean...
其实不一定
No, it doesn't.
罗宾绝对秘密策划了一个
...that Robin is planning a surprise
激光枪战彩排晚宴
laser tag rehearsal dinner!
老兄  罗宾才没有安排什么
Dude, Robin is not planning
秘密的激光枪战彩排晚宴呢
a surprise laser tag rehearsal dinner.
她就是有
Yes, she is.
-她没有  -她有的
- No, she isn't. - Yes, she is.
我根本没有
No, I'm not!
她有的
Yes, she is.
她真的没有
No, she isn't.
那她为什么假装
Then why did she pretend
嘲笑说这主意蠢到家了
to ridicule it as an idiotic idea?
因为这主意真的蠢到家了
Because it is an idiotic idea.
如果罗宾真的有安排什么惊喜
If Robin actually was planning a surprise,
难道她不会告诉她的首席伴娘吗
don't you think she would tell her maid of honor?
她不告诉你  是因为你保守秘密的能力
She didn't tell you 'cause you can keep a secret
就像我牙医收车钥匙一样
the way my dentist keeps his car keys.
你们不认识他  可他把钥匙搞丢了
You don't know him, but he's lost them...
两次
like, twice.
其实只有一次
Actually, just once, and...
另一次是放在其他口袋里了
that time they were in his other pocket.
你说我守不住秘密
I can't keep a secret?
他说得有道理  莉莉
He does have a point, Lily.
你这人是出了名的大嘴巴
You're kind of famous for the old blabbity-blabbity.
你和黛比午餐吃得如何
How was lunch with Debbie?
挺好的  她怀孕了
Great. She's pregnant!
-糟了  她叫我不要告诉别人的  -为什么
- I'm not supposed to tell anybody. - Why not?
因为她正在办离婚
Because she's getting a divorce.
我怎么又说了
Damn it!
黛比要离婚了吗
Debbie's getting a divorce?
没错  她老公被她捉奸在床
Yeah, she walked in on her husband having sex.
莉莉  你到底是怎么了
Oh! Come on, Lily.
我们还是不要太深入细节
Well, maybe we don't need to know every gory...
小三是个男的
With a man.
艾得仁  你嘴巴闭紧点好吗
Will you get it together, Aldrin?!
你还好吧  莉莉
You okay, Lily?
那个小三还是她腹中骨肉的亲爹
And that guy's the father of the baby.
我要去休息一下
I gotta go lie down.
故事回到今天早些时候
Which brings us to earlier today,
罗宾当时正在安排一场假的彩排晚宴
when Robin was setting up the decoy rehearsal dinner,
里面摆满了假酒
complete with fake booze.
离彩排晚宴还有一小时
想用这个来充当威士忌吗
Trying to pass this off as Scotch,
地球人都知道这只是苹果汁
and we all know it's apple juice.
典型的被苹果汁灼伤食道
Typical apple juice burn.
巴尼  这些酒都是真的
Yes, Barney, the booze is real.
食物也是真的
The food is real.
说到这儿  培根卷无花果在哪儿呢
Ooh, speaking of which, where are the bacon-wrapped figs?
我看应该是
Probably at...
放在玩激光枪战的地方了吧
...the laser tag place,
那里才是真正举办彩排晚宴的地方
where the real rehearsal dinner's going down.
我说得对吗  西奥多
Isn't that right, Theodore?
巴尼  根本就没有激光枪战
Barney, there is no laser tag.
我们会好好享用一顿美餐
We're gonna have a nice dinner,
小酌几杯
some drinks, and then,
按罗宾的说法
according to Robin,
如果她的伊迪斯阿姨喝太醉
if her Aunt Edith gets drunk enough,
她会摘下自己的假发  然后大家一起把它当冰球打
she'll take off her wig and they'll play hockey with it.
胡说八道
Poppycock!
你知道她是怎么打算的
You know how she's gonna do it,
马上告诉我
and you're gonna tell me!
否则  我就把我的脸
Or do I have to get my face
继续贴近你的脸
even closer to yours?
为什么你不用这种方法
How come you're not getting
逼问一下我呢
uncomfortably close to my face?
也许这事我也有份
I could be in on it, too.
你觉得可能吗  莉莉
'Course you could, Lil.
我很擅长保守秘密
I can keep a secret.
莉莉  你别逗我了
Lily, don't make me laugh.
你守不住秘密
I'd trust you with a secret
就像马修忍不住要吃流行秘密牌爆米花一样
as much as I'd trust Marshall with Pop Secret.
我能守住秘密
I can keep a secret!
我非常擅长保守秘密
I can keep a secret real good.
我能把一个秘密保守成高级机密
I can keep a secret like nobody's business,
因为它不关任何人的事
'cause it is nobody's business.
因为它是秘密
'Cause it's a secret,
而我就要保密
and I'm keeping it!
马修会自己剃背上的体毛吗
Does Marshall shave his back?
不  我帮他剃  该死的
No, I shave it for him. Damn it!
我应该问问马修
I should call Marshall.
他肯定知情
I bet he's in on this.
如果他真存在的话
If he really exists.
先不说你要去芝加哥的秘密
Setting aside the fact that I've kept your whole
我守口如瓶
"Moving to Chicago" thing a secret,
你今晚不是应该打扮成列勃拉斯吗
aren't you supposed to be dressed like Liberace right now?
首先
Okay, first of all,
如果我现在就穿成那样
if I showed up in costume,
到时候华丽出场的惊艳感和壮丽感
it would steal from the surprise and spectacle
就没有了
of my grand entrance.
其次  我不干了
And second of all, I'm not doing that.
为什么
Why not?
因为打扮成列勃拉斯不难  但是...
Because dressing like Liberace is easy, but...
好的  四四拍  升E调
Uh, yes, 4/4, E-sharp...
主大调...
major...
让我们来演奏一些美妙的音乐吧
Let's make something beautiful, shall we?
不如今天就这样吧
I think that's enough for today.
我知道这次惊喜的具体安排了
Okay, I figured out how this is gonna go down.
首先  冰块"用完"了
We're gonna "run out" of ice,
罗宾就会叫我出去买
and Robin's gonna ask me to go get some,
猜猜怎么样  整个镇上唯一卖冰的地方
and lo and behold, the only place that sells ice
隔壁刚好就是当地的激光枪战场
in this whole town is right next to the local laser taggery.
我进去之后...
I go inside and...
惊喜
Surprise!
美味的晚餐  朋友们家人们都在
Beautiful dinner, family and friends,
游戏币免费拿  还有越野赛车游戏机
free game tokens and an Off-Road arcade game
被调整过可以无限涡轮加速
that's rigged for unlimited turbos!
这个主意实在是太蠢...
That is the single stupidest...
简直难以置信
Guys, you aren't gonna believe this.
制冰机居然坏了
The ice machine is broken.
是吗
Is it now?
喵了个咪  居然会这么巧
Well, dog my cats, what are the chances?
所以要怎么办呢
Huh? What do we do?
好吧  我可以去买点冰回来
Well, I guess I could go get some ice.
不用了  他们会派人送的
Uh, no, they'll send someone.
好吧  你强迫我吧  我愿意
All right, fine. Twist my arm. I'll do it.
不过说真的
But seriously, Hmm?
那边真的都准备好了吗
did you get everything set up over there?
食物够吗  枪的数量够吗
Do you have enough food, have enough guns?
给斯丁森奶奶备好加大感应衣了吗  她...
Did you get a vest extender for Grandma Stinson? She's...
你到底在说什么啊
What are you talking about?
亲爱的  你演技真棒  好爱你
Oh, babe, you're so good at this. I love it.
行了  我们到时候见
All right, I'll see you guys over there.
说错了  我马上回来
I mean, be right back.
巴尼  巴尼  彩排晚宴马上就开始了
Barney, Barney, this is our rehearsal dinner, okay?
不许离开场地
Do not leave the premises.
向我保证你不会去其他地方
Promise me you're not going anywhere.
好吧
Fine.
说出来
Say it.
说  你保证不会离开
Say you promise you won't leave.
我保证不会离开
I promise I won't leave.
然后我离开了  你知道吗
So I left. And what do you know,
卖冰的地方真的在一家激光枪战旁边
the ice store is right next to a laser tag place!
完全不是  隔了六英里
No, it isn't! It's six miles away
而且还是反方向
he opposite direction.
而且我说了不让你去
And I told you not to go!
可是你还说过
Yeah, well, you also told me
婚礼的时候不想要戒熊
didn't want a ring bear at the wedding.
戒童
Ring bear-er!
谁都知道肯定没好结果  重点是
We all know how great that's gonna be. The point is,
我佯装被她骗过了
I played along with her plan,
表现得很"自然"  以免毁掉惊喜
and I acted "natural" so I wouldn't spoil the surprise.
法汉普顿激光酒吧
我的天啊
Oh, my goodness!
激光酒吧
Laser tag?!
冰店  六英里外
也许我应该进去一下
Maybe I should go in here for a minute,
没什么  就随便看看
just check it out for no apparent reason.
这是什么
And what's this?
解放双手的游戏币专用包
My hands-free token satchel?
还有一辈子免费续杯的啤酒专用杯
And my free lifetime refill root beer mug?
所以过去的两个月里
So for the past two months
每个周日晚上
when we were letting you use our apartment
我们都会让你用我们的公寓练琴
to practice the piano every Sunday night,
你都干什么了
what were you doing?
只要是最有价值球员  走步犯规也没事吗
Oh, so that's not traveling 'cause he's the MVP?
拜托
Come on!
巴尼去哪里了  有人看到过他吗
Where's Barney? Has anyone seen him?
罗宾  泰德不打算
Robin, Ted's totally bailing
在婚礼的时候演奏钢琴了
on playing the piano for you and Barney.
真的吗  你不用发善心饶过我们的
Oh, really? Ted, you didn't have to not do that.
不过谢谢你
But thank you.
可是他保证过  说话要算数
But he promised! A promise is a promise.
曾经说出的承诺
You can't say you're gonna do something
怎么能说取消就取消
and then suddenly do something completely different!
你怎么因为这件事这么激动
Why are you getting so worked up about this?
因为我会这样  明显是为了一件
Because, obviously, I'm worked up for a different
类似但不一样的事情而激动
but somewhat similar reason.
你们应该问下我的
And someone should ask me about it!
抱歉  我现在没时间听你诉苦  莉莉
I'm sorry. I don't have time for your drama right now, Lily.
我的未婚夫不见了
My fiance is missing.
马修接受了法官的工作
Marshall got picked to be a judge.
他没跟我商量就接受了
He took the job without even asking me.
去不成意大利了
Italy's off!
我现在有空听你诉苦了
I have time for your drama.
我还那么努力地学习意大利语
And my Italian was getting so good.
去意大利人的工作我是再见
好多伤心啊
等等  你们已经把公寓转租了
But wait, you guys already sublet the apartment.
行李都打包好了
You're already packed.
马修还借走了我的罗塞塔石  结果弄丢了
Marshall already borrowed and lost my Rosetta Stone.
与著名帮助译解了古埃及象形文字石碑的
同名翻译软件
自私的混蛋
That selfish bastard!
抱歉莉莉  喂
Sorry, Lil. Hello.
我也很生气
Okay, I'm mad, too.
你有理由生气
I should hope so.
凭什么他的梦想就比你的梦想重要
All of a sudden, his dream is more important than yours?
而且他甚至没跟你商量一下
And he did it behind your back.
太混烂[意大利腔]
Bastardo!
他肯定不是故意伤我心的
He would never hurt me intentionally.
我会故意伤他的
I'll hurt him intentionally.
无耻混蛋
Molto bastardo!
你这样说真是太贴心了
That's sweet of you to say.
你这辈子永远不是马修的对手
You could never take Marshall in a million years,
但你这样说太贴心了
but that's sweet of you to say.
显然  巴尼去了激光枪战场
Well, apparently, Barney went to the laser tag place
去找惊喜彩排晚宴
looking for a surprise rehearsal dinner.
他没找到  于是威胁
When he didn't find one, he threatened
要把小吃店服务员的脑袋
to dunk the snack bar guy's head
扣篮进一桶滚烫的干酪玉米片中
into a vat of scalding nacho Whiz.
他被扣留了  等警察来拘捕
He's being held until the police arrive
我要来点你的苹果汁
I need your apple juice.
于是我们就到这里了
And here we are.
咱们的哑谜游戏玩得够久了
Now, I believe this charade has gone on long enough.
直奔主题  开始惊喜激光枪战彩排好吗
Can we please get to the surprise laser tag rehearsal?
根本没有激光枪战彩排晚宴好吗
Hey, there is no surprise laser tag rehearsal dinner!
好的  但如果我可以提出相反观点的话
Okay, but if I may offer an opposing view.
当然有啦
Of course there is!
这里到处是蛛丝马迹
This place is lousy with clues.
他真的是保安吗
Is he even really a security guard?
因为他看起来超级像送三明治
Because he looks an awful lot like a non-Pakistani version
到我公司的非巴基斯坦外卖小子
of the guy who delivers sandwiches at my office.
还有
Also...
"激光枪战"单词的字母个数和"彩排"一样
"Laser tag" has the same number of letters as "rehearsal."
"激光游戏"有8个字母  "彩排"有9个
Laser tag has eight, rehearsal has nine.
如果把这些字母重新排序  再加点别的字母
And if you rearrange the letters and add some other ones,
就是  "准备好  巴尼  迎接史上最大的惊喜
it says, "Get ready, Barney, for the biggest surprise ever,
你这个帅气的小..."
you handsome son of a..."
没有足够字母拼写"杂种"了
and then not quite enough letters for "bitch,"
但做得好  罗宾
but good try, Robin.
这太疯狂了  巴尼
This is crazy, Barney.
我们不能这样维持婚姻
We-We can't have a marriage like this.
婚姻应该以诚实和信任为基础
A marriage has to be built on honesty and trust
还有那些莉莉马修夫妻之道的废话
and all of that Lily- and-Marshall crap.
我以为我们的婚姻是以诚实和信任为基础的
I though our marriage was built on honesty and trust
还有那些莉莉马修夫妻之道的废话
and all that Lily- and-Marshal crap.
我现在感觉好孤单
I just feel so alone right now.
你不孤单  我在这里
Well, you're not. I'm here.
我知道你可以保守秘密
And I know you can keep a secret.
是啊
Yeah, right.
这样吧
Tell you what.
我再向你透露个秘密如何
How about I let you in on another secret?
非常大的秘密
Something bigger.
比芝加哥的事还大吗
Bigger than Chicago?
你不是开玩笑吧
Are you kidding?
不  想来宣布这件事吗
Nope. Want to do the honors?
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
计划稍稍有变
there's been a slight change of plan.
好吧  好吧
Fine! Fine.
你是对的  罗宾
You're right, Robin.
婚姻的重点不是玩疯狂的恶作剧
Marriage isn't about playing crazy pranks.
也不是说些精心策划的专家级长篇谎言
It isn't about telling long expertly crafted lies
来掩护这些恶作剧
to cover those pranks...
你是怎么解开手铐的
How'd you get out of those handcuffs?
不是雇演员扮演保安
...and hiring actors to play security guards
也不是砸下大笔银子去做
and spending exorbitant amounts of money on things
巨大的假激光枪战标志
like giant, fake laser tag signs.
不  重点是诚实
No, it's about honesty.
你穿六号冰鞋对吗
Size six skate, right?
是的
Yeah.
本着这种精神  我得说实话
And in that spirit, I got to be honest.
以后时不时地
Every now and then,
我会对你说谎  我就是这样
I am gonna lie to you. I just am.
哪怕是为了给你美妙的惊喜  我也会说谎
If it's in the interest of an amazing surprise, that is.
你会被愚弄  蒙蔽
You're gonna get bamboozled, hoodwinked.
见鬼  我就直说了吧
Heck, I'll just say it.
雪花会飘落在你身上
You're gonna get snowed.
这里为什么会下雪
Why is it snowing in here?
穿上冰鞋吧
Put on the skates.
我们得走了
We gotta go.
去哪里
Where?
我们去哪里
Where are we going?
参加彩排晚宴  小傻瓜
To the rehearsal dinner, silly.
咱们让派对开始吧
Let's get this party started.
什么
What?!
惊喜
Surprise!
这是怎么回事
What-What is going on?
我知道这周末你有多想回加拿大
I know how much you wanted to be in Canada this weekend.
所以我把加拿大带到你身边
So I brought Canada to you.
这是韦恩・格雷茨基的签名照
Oh, and here's an autographed picture of Wayne Gretzky.
谢谢
Thanks.
这个家伙不是保安
And this guy's not really a security guard.
曾经有一个男孩 *
* Once there was this boy who
西装不离身  "传奇"不离口 *
* Wore a lot of suits and said that stuff was "Legendary"
他与人击掌无数 *
* He gave lots of high fives
而且发誓 *
* And swore...
他永远不会结婚 *
* That he would never get married
他真的觉得他是认真的 *
* He really thought he meant it
谢谢你让我参与这个秘密
Thanks for letting me in on this.
哪怕是在最后一刻
Even if it was at the very end.
我的荣幸
My pleasure.
对了
Oh, and by the way,
我还有一个秘密没说
there's one more secret I've been keeping.
我应该上钢琴课的那些晚上
All those nights I was supposed to be taking piano lessons?
其实我在上花样滑冰课
I was actually taking figure skating lessons!
孩子们  要想学会花样滑冰
Kids, it takes more than two months
两个月是不够的
to learn how to figure skate.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
-我会还以颜色的  -放马过来
- I'm gonna get you back, you know? - Bring it.
并且  她也发誓永远不会结婚 *
* And swore she'd also never get married
她真的觉得她是认真的 *
* She really thought she meant it.
真不敢相信这些是你安排的
I can't believe you did all of this.
我以为你不喜欢加拿大
Hey, I thought you didn't like Canada.
开什么玩笑  我爱加拿大
Are you kidding? I love Canada.
我滴个亲娘
Holy musk ox,
那不是加拿大传奇医生弗雷德里克・班廷吗
isn't that legendary Canadian Dr. Frederick Banting
1924年  我发现了胰岛素
In 1924, I discovered insulin.
受死吧  糖尿病
Take that, diabetes.
看  这是马尼托巴省的当地人诺曼・布瑞奇
Hey, look, it's Manitoba's native son, Norman Breakey.
不用谢  全世界
You're welcome, world.
享受我的发明吧  滚漆筒
Enjoy my invention, the paint roller.
当然了  你认识艾伦・锡克
And of course, you know Alan Thicke.
瞧你
Hey, hey, you...
这里最美丽的女孩
...are the prettiest girl in the place.
谢谢你  艾伦
Oh, thank you, Alan.
行啦  行啦
All right, all right, all right.
见到你真开心
Good to see you.
看  这是路易丝・普瓦里耶
Hey, look, it's Louise Poirier,
我想她效力的公司
who I think worked for the company
可能发明了神奇文胸
that probably created Wonderbra.
再见啦  旧式束身衣
别蹭了  行啦  行啦
Let go, okay, okay.
加拿大还帮手打赢了两次世界大战
Canadians also helped win two world wars...
为全世界奉献了尼尔・杨  威廉・夏特纳
...and gave the world Neil Young, William Shatner,
前者音乐人  后者名演员
里奥纳德・科恩  帕米拉・安德森
Leonard Cohen, Pamela Anderson,
前者诗人兼创作歌手  后者性感演员
四分之一的巴尼・斯丁森
one quarter of Barney Stinson,
即食土豆泥  当然最好的作品  就是你
instant mashed potatoes, and best of all, you.
谢谢
Thank you.